1: Hello?
2: Yeah, hello
1: Hello
2: Please can I speak to
2: Mr Jones please
1: Yeah, you're talking to
1: Mr Jones please. How may I help you?
2: You're John
2: Smith. You
2: speaking to... you
2: to Mr
2: Grequeelance(?) calling from
2: FBI department over here in New York
1: Sorry?
2: You speaking to Agent
2: Grequeelance(?)
2: I'm calling from the FBI Department
2: over here in New York
1: OK
2: Yeah
2: How are you today?
1: I'm all right. How are you?
2: Ah, listen to me, we got your email.
2: Your email, you said that
2: I'm Anthony(?) but I do not want to handle
2: this through my office
2: given the amount involved. Could you
2: [call me]? on your [sic] [home] phone?
2: Please do not [contact] me at my office
2: email again. This is not something
2: I want to share with my partners
2: Thank you, John Smith, Attorney at Law
1: OK
2: Is this email from you?
1: This email is not from me
1: I've been receiving series
1: of reg conses(?) but
1: [about?] this email, I don't know.
1: Can I be frank(?) with you?
1: I don't know how, how my
1: how my account was
1: spammed(?) and how it was
1: used for
1: such(?). I don't know
2: Yeah, it had to be [talking over each other]
2: We have no problem
2: You listen carefully: we have no problem
2: OK, don't you have a
2: personal email? Don't tell me(?) personal
2: email? Private email?
1: Yeah
1: Yes, I do.
2: OK 1: Yes, I
1: do 2: I
2: OK, mmm...
2: You just have to listen carefully
2: You have the
2: sum of 8.3 million dollars(?)
2: coming to your name
2: ATM card
2: They said(?) this is an ATM card
2: Yeah
2: All you need is to do is
2: uh, to send $150
2: for shipping and activation
2: fees
1: [laughter]
2: Hello?
1: Oh, why geez(?), are you sure
1: this call is from
1: FBI?
1: hmmm? 2: Yeah
2: this call is from
2: FBI over here in
1: no, no, no, no, no 2: I just
2: I'm calling [crosstalk]